(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-25T12:32:40.711101",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
幾千の時を巡って今
Crossing through thousands of years,
僕ら出逢えたの
we've finally met.
ほら 見失わない
Look, I won't lose you.
ように 手を離さないで
So that you won't let go of my hand...
星降る海
[Title: Starry Sea]
ねえ 耳をすませて
Hey, listen closely
星の降る音 掻き消えるでしょう
The sound of falling stars will be drowned out, won't it?
もっと 近くに来て
Come closer to me,
誰も知らない 世界が待ってるの
A world unknown to anyone is waiting for us.
手を取って 踊りましょう
Take my hand and let's dance.
始まりの合図なら 響かせば
If we ring out the signal for the beginning,
歌をラララ 響けラララ 暗がりの道も突き
Singing la-la-la, echoing la-la-la, pushing through the dark path
光がテラスの
The light illuminates...
空 踏みの向こう
Beyond the steps of the sky,
君の元まで響くように歌えるかな
Can I sing so it reaches you?
どんな時も ここにいてるよ
I'll be right here no matter what,
祈っているからさ ほら
Because I'm praying, look—
キラキラ輝く星は 色褪せず太古から
Sparkling stars shine eternally from ancient times,
手足続けてる 君と辿り着けるさ
Reaching out step by step, I'll surely reach you.
心みは合いたい
My heart wants to meet you,
誰か描いて らしいばん みたいね
Like someone sketching a vision of you.
そっと 目を開けてみて
Gently open your eyes and see,
見えるものだけがリアルじゃないの
Not only what you can see is real.
君といる世界は 永遠の記憶に眠るのさ
The world I share with you sleeps in eternal memory—
歌をラララ 響けラララ
Singing la-la-la, echoing la-la-la,
潮の道引きが 道導いてくれるの
The tide's ebb and flow guides the way.
途切れかけた 夢を見ても大丈夫 一人にはしないよ
Even if a fading dream visits, it's alright—I won't leave you alone.
何度だって 互いの引力で 引き寄せ合うんだよ
No matter how many times, our mutual gravity will pull us together.
空 海の匂い 君に届くかな
Will the scent of the sky and sea reach you?
距離なんてないのかな
Is there really no distance between us?
どんな時も 聞こえるところで 見守っているからさ
Because I'm watching over you from a place where I can always be heard—
ほら クシャクシャになって笑う日を
Look, the days we laugh all crinkled up,
集めて紡いだミラー 踏み出す先も君と心の振るわせて
Gathering and spinning a mirror, stepping forward with you and letting our hearts resonate.
可能性は 物語を巡るわ
Possibility traverses the story,
は
Ah...
にこたんがキター！バーチャルデュバイスフロプロのお笑いタレント、五金にこです！
Nicotan is here! I'm Nicotan, comedy talent of Virtual Device Flowglow!
にこたんだよー！誕生日だー！やったー！
It's Nicotan! It's my birthday! Yay!
にこたん初の生誕ライブ「星円-Firestella Diva-」にご来場いただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for attending Nicotan's first birthday live, "Hoshien -Firestella Diva-"!
本日のハッシュタグは、#にこたん生誕2026！
Today's hashtag is #NicotanBirthday2026!
「たん」はにこたんの「たん」なんでひらがなです！こちらでね、スクショたくさん撮って感想どしどしポストしてください！
"Tan" in Nicotan is in hiragana! Take lots of screenshots here and post your impressions!
頼んます！
I'm counting on you!
今回のタイトル「星円-Firestella Diva-」、こちらは「火」「星」「虎」の3つの要素を掛け合わせたトリプルミーニング、にこたんが作っちゃいました！
The title "Hoshien -Firestella Diva-" is a triple meaning combining "fire", "star", and "tiger", which I created!
まあ、にこたんが星で、でみんなから火をもらっててみたいな！フェスでさ、
Well, I'm the star, and I get fire from everyone, sort of! At the fest,
初めてのフェスでみんなのペンライトはかかってたりでしょ？あれはね、火だったの！このライブの匂わせをしていたわけです。
at my first fest, everyone's penlights were lit, right? That was fire! It was hinting at this live.
計画通りってわけさ！今回はたくさんの
Just as planned! This time, lots of...
「ディーバ」とそんなにーこたんの炎を感じられるような感じで
"Diva" — with a feel where you can feel Nico-tan's flame,
たくさん歌っていく歌手がメインのライブになっております！
singing lots of songs, this is a singer-focused live!
1曲目は星降る海を歌わせていただきました。
The first song was "Ocean of Falling Stars".
皆さんどうりでしたでしょうか？
How did you all like it?
にこたん、セクシーだったでしょうか？
Was Nico-tan sexy?
この後はゲストのディーバたちとの時間です。
After this is time with the guest divas.
それではゲストパート、レッツゴー！
Now, guest part, let's go!
涙が夜に溶けて
My tears melt into the night,
空が今日も遠くなる
and once again the sky gets farther today
未来が閉じたように
As if my future was filed away,
暗闇が満ちている
the darkness clouds my eyes
Aa, minikui kokoro mo
Ah, my heart is hideous,
kasuresou na kotoba mo
and my words sound hoarse from my throat
Subete misukashita you ni
But as if they were seeing right through me,
hoshi ga kagayaite ita
the stars were shining
夜たかのように高く 空をかけていけたら
If I were able to race across the sky and back,
綺麗だってはやされて 特別になれたのに
I would've been special, acclaimed for my beauty, but...
そう、うつむいた目には 憧れしかうつらない
Yes, my downcast eyes reflect nothing but yearning
誰かの描いた地図じゃ ともる場所は探せない
I can't search for my place to shine with someone else's map
あぁ、僕らの現状は じれったくフラットして
Ah, our current situation is falling pathetically flat
気を抜けばあすが 昨日になってしまう
If we let our guards down, tomorrow will become yesterday
これはそう、きょうを あきらめなかったゆえのストーリー
This is the story created because I didn't give up on today
風切り羽響かせて 空を目指して
Let your flight feathers resonate and aim for the sky
惨めになっていやに なったって輝いてる
Even if you become miserable or hate your shining dream
夢を叶える羽は とっくのとうに生えていた
The wings to make it come true sprouted a long time ago
吐き出す息が白寒（しろさめ）て
The breath I exhale is cooling to white,
声も聞こえなくなって
and I can't hear my voice anymore
燃え上がる体温が夜空を焦がすまで
Until the flaring warmth I radiate sets the night sky ablaze
誰よりもっともっと向こうえって羽ばたいた星の
Telling themselves to go further than anyone else...
一瞬を
The stars took flight — and they'll have their moment
あぁ、夜空はずっと待っている 灯る日を、待っている
Ah, that's what the night sky has always been waiting for
きっと、きット
Surely, surely...
「いつか」なんてごまかして 「誰か」になすりつけて
Deceiving with a "sometime" / Putting blame on "someone"
「どこか」なんてなぐさめて 「何か」にすがっている
Finding solace in "somewhere" / Clinging to "something"
あぁ、それこそが僕だ 汚れきった心だ
Ah, that is the true me — a heart rotten to the core
夜たかにはなれないな だからきょうを飛んだんだ
I can't become a nightjar, that's why I flew over today
あぁ、僕らの結末は 面白いほどナーバスで
Ah, our conclusion is as nerve-wrecking as it's interesting
予測なんてひとつも あてにならないから
Because we can't count on a single prediction to be right
これはまだ僕を あきらめなかったゆえのストーリー
This is still the story created because I didn't give up on myself
枯れたのどを響かせて 後悔を追い越して
Let your hoarse throat resonate, surpass your regrets
世界にとって僕にとって ふさわしかった役なんて
The role this world wants for me, that's fit for me...
要らない知らない所詮僕は僕だった それならどうかこの
I don't need it, I am just myself. In that case, I pray...
涙を忘れないで 疲れ果ててこの
that I won't forget these tears until I fall from this sky
今よりもっともっと向こうえって羽ばたいた星が
Telling themselves to go further than ever...
泣いている あぁ、夜空が白けだしている
The stars took flight and now they're crying out
日がのぼりだしている そっと
Ah, the night sky fades, the sun starts to rise gently
あれから始まって これから終わっていく
It started back then, and starting now, it'll end
ひとつ、ひとつ、一瞬を 確かめていく
One by one, we're ascertaining our moments
誰とも同じじゃない 誰にも似ていない
They're not the same for everyone, not like anyone else
一人、一人、とても不確かな 空を飛んでいるのさ
One by one, we're all flying over a very uncertain sky
僕らの現状は 気持ちひとつでシャープして
Our current situation is going sharp with a single feeling
びびっていたあしたを 昨日にかえてしまえる
Turning the tomorrow we feared into yesterday
これはそう、きょうを あきらめなかったゆえのストーリー
This is, yes, the story created because I didn't give up on today
風切り羽響かせて 空を目指して
Let your flight feathers resonate and aim for the sky
惨めになっていやに なったって輝いてる
Even if you become miserable or hate your shining dream
夢を叶える羽は とっくのとうに生えていた
The wings to make it come true sprouted a long time ago
吐き出す息が白寒（しろさめ）て
The breath I exhale is cooling to white,
声も聞こえなくなって
and I can't hear my voice anymore
燃え上がる体温が夜空を焦がすまで
Until the flaring warmth I radiate sets the night sky ablaze
だって 僕は 星だから
Because I am a star,
Stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気付いていた
I'm sure you had already noticed it.
僕の心の中で描いた それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
The monologue drawn deep within my heart, which I'll share now.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say,
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
and walls I could never break through, all along.
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
The scent of morning suddenly wafting in,
どうしようもなく憎々しくて
feeling unbearably hateful,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていた
I sat in the corner of the room, trembling with my knees hugged.
太陽なんかいらないから
I don't need any sunshine,
明けないでいて
so please don't let dawn break.
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Stretching out that hand so it reaches someone,
僕だって君と同じ 特殊なんかじゃないから
Because I'm not special, just like you,
そうさ僕は夜を歌う Stellar stellar
That's right, I sing to the night, stellar stellar.
ありったけの輝きで今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まらない
With all my brilliance tonight, the music will never ever stop.
そうだ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
That's right, what I always wanted to be
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
was never a Cinderella waiting for her prince,
迎えに行く王子様だ
but the prince who goes to meet her.
だって 僕は 星だから
Because I am a star!
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
Someday, the light of love you kindle in your eyes
時を超えて
will transcend time
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を確実に一つ壊すだろう
and surely shatter a dream of this rapidly perishing world.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallowing your hesitation,
君が望むモノは何?
what is it that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に微かな明日はあるの?
Is there a faint tomorrow at the end of such greedy longing?
子どもの頃夢に見てた 古の魔法のように
Like the ancient magic I dreamed of in my childhood,
闇さえ砕く力で 微笑む君に会いたい
with power to shatter even the darkness, I want to see you smile.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の勇気
In these trembling hands lies the courage of a plucked flower.
想いだけが頼る全て 光を呼び覚ます 願いを
With only feelings to rely on, I awaken the light... My wish.
いつか君も誰かの為に 強い力を望むのだろう
Someday, you too will surely desire great power for someone's sake.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に 未知の言葉が生まれて来る
In the night when love seized your heart, unknown words are born.
迷わずに行けるなら 心が砕けてもいいわ
If I can go without hesitation, I don't care if my heart shatters.
いつも目の前の悲しみに 立ち向かう為の 呪文が欲しい
I want a spell to always confront the sorrow right before me.
君はまだ夢見る記憶 私は眠らない明日
You are still dreaming memories; I am a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を 勝ち取る為に進むわ
I will press forward to win the miracle of our meeting.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の刃
In these trembling hands lies the blade of a plucked flower.
想いだけが生きる全て 心に振りかざす 願いを
With only feelings to keep me alive, I brandish them in my heart... My wish.
囚われた太陽の輝く 不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
When I loved books about Wonderland where the captive sun shines,
願いはきっと叶うと 教えるお伽話を信じた
I believed the fairy tales teaching that wishes surely come true.
静かに咲き乱れていた 古の魔法優しく
Blooming quietly, the ancient magic
世界を変える力が その手にあると喚く
cries out that the power to change the world is in your hands.
終わらない夢を見よう 君と行く時の中で
Let's see a never-ending dream within the time I walk with you.
想いだけが生きる全て 命を作るのは 願いを
With only feelings to keep me alive, what creates life is... My wish.
君はまだ夢見る記憶 私は眠らない明日
You are still dreaming memories; I am a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を 勝ち取る為に進むわ
I will press forward to win the miracle of our meeting.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の刃
In these trembling hands lies the blade of a plucked flower.
想いだけが生きる全て 心に振りかざす 願いを
With only feelings to keep me alive, I brandish them in my heart... My wish.
囚われた太陽の輝く 不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
When I loved books about Wonderland where the captive sun shines,
願いはきっと叶うと 教えるお伽話を信じた
I believed the fairy tales teaching that wishes surely come true.
静かに咲き乱れていた 古の魔法優しく
Blooming quietly, the ancient magic
世界を変える力が その手にあると喚く
cries out that the power to change the world is in your hands.
終わらない夢を見よう 君と行く時の中で
Let's see a never-ending dream within the time I walk with you.
想いだけが生きる全て 命を作るのは 願いを
With only feelings to keep me alive, what creates life is... My wish.
囚われた太陽の輝く
Where the captive sun shines,
不思議の国の音楽が好きだった頃
When I loved the music of Wonderland,
願いはきっと叶うと 叶うと信じてる
I believe that wishes will surely, surely come true.
欲しいおとぎ話を聞かせて
Tell me the fairy tales I yearn to hear.
光の陰で
In the shadow of the light...
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
Someday the light of love that you shine in your eyes
時を超えて
will transcend time,
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を
and surely destroy one of the dreams
確実に一つ壊すだろう
of a world rushing toward ruin.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallowing down all hesitation,
君が望むモノは何?
what is it that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に
In the path of such greedy yearning,
儚い明日はあるの?
is there a transient tomorrow?
子どもの頃夢に見てた 古の魔法のように
Like the ancient magic I dreamed of as a child,
闇さえ砕く力で 微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet you smiling with power that shatters even the darkness.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の勇気
In these trembling hands lies the courage of a plucked flower;
想いだけが頼る全て 光を呼び覚ます願い
feelings are all I rely on, a wish that awakens the light.
いつか君も誰かの為に 強い力を望むのだろう
Someday you too will wish for great power for someone's sake.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に 未知の言葉が生まれてくる
On a night when love captures the heart, unknown words are born.
迷わずに行けるなら 心が砕けてもいいわ
If I can go without hesitation, even if my heart breaks, it's fine.
いつも目の前の悲しみに 立ち向かうための 呪文が欲しい
I want a spell to face the sorrow always right before my eyes.
君はまだ夢見る記憶 私は眠らない明日
You are still memories dreaming; I am a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を 勝ち取る為に進むわ
I will press forward to win the miracle of our meeting.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の刃
In these trembling hands lies the blade of a plucked flower;
想いだけが生きる全て 心に振りかざす 願い
feelings are all that live, a wish brandished in my heart.
サンドリオン
[Cendrillon]
朝まで踊る 夢だけ見せて
Let me see only dreams, dancing until morning.
時計の針が解く魔法を
The magic untied by the clock's hands—
曖昧な指 誘う階段
ambiguous fingers invite me up the stairs,
三段飛ばしに跳ねていく
bounding up three steps at a time.
馬車の中で 震えていた
Trembling inside the carriage,
歪んだ古着 めくりめく夜の舞踏
in tattered old clothes, through the spinning night ball.
知らぬ顔を探す 囁くあの声が
Searching for an unfamiliar face, that whispering voice
握り締めた刃 月夜突き刺したって
pierced the moonlit night with the blade I clenched tightly.
皆し後つどう後ろ 笑み仮面に描いて
Gathered behind, drawing smiles on our masks,
偽りのない一瞬さえ 裸で包む
wrapping even a fleeting moment of falsehood bare.
ざわめく サブール
[Cendrillon]
灰の中で 赤く
Glowing red in the ashes,
溶けて混ざる ガラスの靴
the glass slipper melts and mixes in.
今さら帰る 震えているの
Returning now, are you trembling?
あなたが目をやる 時計
The clock where you cast your eyes—
靴脱ぎ踊る スロープ抜けて
slipping off our shoes and dancing, slipping past the slope,
望むまで伸びる 指の隙間で
through the gaps of fingers stretching as far as desired.
少しずつ 朽ち付けて
Little by little, letting it decay,
走る衝動 背骨抜けいく 絶望
the racing impulse pierces through the spine—despair.
鐘は鳴らさないで あなたに膝まずき
Don't ring the bell; kneeling before you,
まだダメと叫んだ 右手が突き刺す サヨナラ
my right hand shouting "not yet" pierces through—goodbye.
消せない 一生分の香水にまとう秘密
A secret draped in an unforgettable lifetime's perfume,
強い瞳 僕の残った仮面を溶かす
your strong eyes melt the mask I had left.
今も耳に あの声が
Even now, that voice in my ears,
突き刺さるの 遠い 呪文
piercing deep—a distant spell,
捨てたグラス越し
through the discarded glass.
光る月が 君に被せたベール
The shining moon places a veil over you.
ドレスの裾で裂いて ティアラは投げ捨て
Tear the hem of the dress, throw away the tiara;
見つめ合う瞳と瞳が 花火を放つ
eyes meeting eyes release fireworks.
孤独な魂が 炎を上げ 光りあう
Lonely souls raise flames and shine together,
その涙 救えないなら
if those tears cannot be saved,
まるでひとり遊びのように
as if playing all alone,
まれ今は あなたに宵しれて
right now, intoxicated by you,
揺れる鼓動を 一つ一つを 刻み付けてたい
I want to carve every single beating pulse into my heart.
とどまれ 熱く濡れて 打ち付ける高まりに
Stay, burning and wet, against this pounding surge—
これ以上は 動けないよ まれペアにしてる
moving no more, as if paired up.
そばにいても 離れたまま 一つになれない流星
Even when close, remaining apart, a shooting star that can't become one.
アルビレオ
Albireo.
[Albireo]
ああ 君が思うよりも 僕は君でいっぱいだ
Ah, I'm so much more full of you than you think.
流星みたいなうつろいを 片時も離さず見たいの
I want to watch your meteor-like fickleness without looking away for even a moment.
ああ 僕が思うよりも 君はずっとずっと遠い
Ah, you are much, much further away than I think.
重なったように見える仕草 苦しくなるほどに美しいな
Gestures that look like they overlap are so beautiful they make my chest ache.
君が好きで感情が 残らず夜空を飾っている
My feelings of "I like you" decorate the night sky completely.
心がまだ言い訳を 愛だなんて呼びたくない
My heart still doesn't want to call this excuse "love".
君は愛に浮かんだ アルビレオを この心奪ったまま
You, the Albireo floating in love, with this heart stolen away—
いらないのなら返してよ 他に欲張もないけどさ
if you don't need it, give it back, even though I have no other greed.
今の相ミスの流星橋が 清爽圏で燃えて
Burning in the stratosphere...
そばにいても 離れたまま 一つになれない流星
Even when close, remaining apart, a shooting star that can't become one.
アルビレオ
Albireo.
何光年先で 輝いてる君に 君に恋をしたんだ
I fell in love with you, shining many light-years away.
何光年先から 測れるほど君の光が眩しすぎて からだ
Your light is so dazzling, measurable from light-years away...
君が好きで感情が それだけで星が回っている
With just my feelings of "I like you", the stars keep spinning.
明日を生きる言い訳を 愛だなんて呼んでみたい
I want to try calling the excuse to live tomorrow "love".
君は愛に浮かんだ アルビレオを この心奪ったまま
You, the Albireo floating in love, with this heart stolen away—
いらないのなら返してよ 他に欲張もないけどさ
if you don't need it, give it back, even though I have no other greed.
今の相ミスの流星橋が 清爽圏で燃えて
Burning in the stratosphere...
そばにいても 離れたまま 一つになれない流星
Even when close, remaining apart, a shooting star that can't become one.
君は愛の色 ざるビレオ この心焦がしたまま
You are the color of love, Albireo, scorching this heart—
誰より近く 恋してて 孤独わけもないのにさ
loving closer than anyone, even though there's no loneliness.
今も温度を超えたかなりが 君を好きと叫ぶ
Screaming "I love you" beyond temperature—
離れてても 消えないまま 二つにならない二十歳 アルビレオ
A binary star that never becomes one, remaining unextinguished even apart, Albireo.
星月夜
[Starry Night]
子どもの頃 見上げた
Looking up when I was a child...
夜の空に 想った
I thought of it in the night sky,
あのひとつひとつに 誰かの願いがこもってる
that each and every one holds someone's wish.
そのひとつが あなたで
That one of them is you,
すぐ隣で 笑ってて 目隠しを止めれるなら
and if you're laughing right next to me, stopping the blinding veil,
この一秒を 切り取って
cutting out this very second...
欲しいよ 夜に
In the night I desire you so,
ただあなたに 会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を 祈るようにそっと 何度も
Gently, like a prayer, over and over,
抱きしめているよ
I'm holding your name close.
Holding it close...
もう私も 大人ね 変わったこと 変わらないこと
I'm an adult now too. What has changed, what hasn't changed...
止まらない時計の針が 冷たいうねりを刻んだ
The hands of the unstoppable clock carved a cold swell.
でもあなたに 出会って
Yet, meeting you,
日々の眩しさを 知って
I came to know the dazzle of each day,
まだ少し怖いけど
though I'm still a bit scared,
今生み出せる気がしてる
I feel like I can create it now.
星降る 夜に 会いたい日が積もるばかり
On a starry night, days of longing just pile up.
あなたの名前を 祈るようにそっと 何度も
Gently, like a prayer, over and over,
抱きしめているよ
I'm holding your name close.
高なる鼓動が 体を追い越していく
My racing heartbeat overtakes my body.
私の名前を 特別にしてくれても
Even if you made my name special,
今はただ抱きしめていたい いつも持ってるよ
right now I just want to hold you close, I'll always hold on to it.
悴んだ手に 温もり
Warmth in numb hands...
目を閉じて その先へ
Close your eyes and head beyond.
星降る 夜に
On a starry night,
ただあなたに 会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を 祈るようにそっと 何度も
Gently, like a prayer, over and over,
抱きしめているよ
I'm holding your name close.
高なる鼓動で
With a racing heartbeat...
裸のまま かけていく
running forth just as I am.
私の名前を 特別にしてくれたの
You made my name special.
あなたが 照らし続けてる
You keep on illuminating it.
星降る 夜に
On a starry night...
ぜいぜいせっせっ うーんずィーイェガー
Sie sind das Essen? Nein, wir sind der Jäger!
Feuerroter Pfeil und Bogen.
踏まれた花の 名前も知らずに
Not knowing the name of the trampled flower,
地に墜ちた鳥は 風を待ち焦がれる
the fallen bird yearns for the wind.
Seid ihr das Essen?
Nein, wir sind der Jäger!
踏みまれた花の 名前も知らずに
地に墜ちた鳥は 風を待ち焦がれる
祈ったところで 何も変わらない
《今》を変えるのは 戦う覚悟だ
屍踏み越えて 進む意志を 嗤う豚よ
家畜の安寧 虚偽の繁栄
死せば餓狼の《自由》を!
囚われた屈辱は 反撃の嚆矢だ
城壁の其の彼方 獲物を屠る《狩人》
奔る《衝動》に 其の身を灼きながら
黄昏に緋を穿つ ――紅蓮の弓矢
矢を番え追い馳せる 標的は逃がさない
矢を放ち追い詰める 決して逃がさない
限界まで引き絞る はじ切れそうな弦
標的が息絶えるまで 何度でも放つ
獲物を殺すのは 凶器でも技術でもない
研ぎ澄ませられた お前自身の殺意だ
Wir sind die Jäger!
炎のように熱く
氷のように冷ややかに
己を矢に込めて
Wir sind die Jäger!
全てを貫いてゆけ
何かを変える事が出来るのは 何かを捨てることが出来るもの
何ひとつリスクなど 背負わないまま…
暗愚の想定 ただの幻影…
今はおぞましい勇気も…
《自由》の尖兵 賭けの攻勢
奔る奴隷に勝利を!
架せられた不条理は 進撃の嚆矢だ
奪われた其的地平《世界》を望む《エレン》
奔る《衝動》に 其の身を侵されながら
黄昏に死を運ぶ ――冥府の弓矢
ieder siegt die Jägerer
炎のように熱く
氷のように冷ややかに
ieder siegt die Jägerer
己を矢に込めて
全てを貫いてゆけ
Angress auf die Titanen
Der Junge von einst bald wird Schwert greifen
Wer nur seine Machtlosigkeit beklagt kann nichts verändern
Der Junge von einst bald wird das schwarze Schwert ergreifen
Hass und Zorn sind eine zweischneidige Klinge
Bald eines Tages wird er dem Schicksal die Zähne zeigen
何を変えることが出来るのは
何かを捨てることが出来るもの
何ひとつリスクなど 背負わないままで
何か叶うなど…
暗愚の想定 ただの幻影…
今も無謀な勇気も…
《自由》の尖兵 賭けの攻勢
奔る奴隷に勝利を!
角度のそしてただの現に いまは無謀な勇気も
自由の先兵 架けの攻勢 走る奴隷に勝利を
架せられた不条理は 進撃の嚆矢だ
奪われた其的地平世界を望むエレン
奔る衝動に 其の身を侵されながら
黄昏に死を運ぶ 冥府の弓矢
Aria, die Tänzerin, die
炎のように熱く
氷のように冷ややかに
Aria, die Tänzerin, die
己を矢に込めて
全てを貫いてゆけ
Aria, die Tänzerin, die
空の午後が綺麗でしょう？
Isn't the afternoon sky beautiful?
綺麗だね。似合うよ、ちまちゃん。
It is. It suits you, Chima-chan.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
いや、今日はね、ちまちゃんとの紅の海を歌っていただいたんだけど、
Today, we had Chima-chan sing "Crimson Sea" with me,
はい。
yes.
なんかね、ちまちゃんのがハイトーンも好きなんだけど、
and I love Chima-chan's high notes,
かっこよさも好きなのよ。
but I also love her coolness.
うん、ありがとう。
Yeah, thank you.
でもなんか、そんな二つを交えられたらいいなと思って今回選びました。
So I chose this song hoping to blend those two sides.
ありがとう！一緒に歌ってくれて。嬉しかったー。
Thank you for singing with me! I was so happy.
え、よかった！
Oh, I'm glad!
ちまちゃん！
Chima-chan!
ちまちゃんとバトルできて楽しかった。
It was fun battling with Chima-chan.
もう大変だったよ、もう。
It was so tough, really!
パッカパッカから嬉しいです。
I'm so happy from the bottom of my heart.
全然、全然。
Not at all, not at all.
え、あのゴーレムは何だったの？
Um, what was that golem?
うん、あれはマッチたの眷属のゴーレムです。
Ah, that was Matchta's subordinate golem.
そうだよね。
That's right.
うん。ありがとう、言わせたみたいになってるけど。
Yeah. Thanks, even though it sounds like I made you say it.
いや、もう強い強かったよ、マッチまちゃんのもうゴーレムが。
No, Match-macha's golem was so strong.
ええ、めちゃくちゃ強かったけど、パオソルちょっとんだよね、にこちゃんに。
Yeah, it was super strong, but Nicotan punched it a bit, right?
そうだよね。
That's right.
にこちゃん強かったからね。
Nicotan was strong, after all.
にこちゃんのおかげでなんかマッチた自身もパワーが、なんかどんどん削られて、
Thanks to Nicotan, Matchta's own power was gradually drained...
ああ！
Ah!
もうだめかもしれない！
Maybe I can't go on!
まだかもしれない！
Maybe I'm done for!
時間がない！
There's no time!
ちまちゃん！
Chima-chan!
ちまちゃん本当にやおめでとう、ありがとう！もうこれからもよろしくねまっかね、バイバ
Chima-chan, truly congratulations, thank you! Let's get along from now on too, bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
終演！
Curtain call!
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Even so, I wanted to dance.
眠れない夜
Sleepless nights
情熱の日はいつしか いつ日にか
The days of passion, someday, somewhere
花から火照っている ホームランはいつか消える
Flushing from flowers, home runs will eventually fade.
ねぇ何もいらないはずだった のにまだ I'm so serious
Hey, I didn't need anything, yet I'm still so serious.
アマノジャキよ
Oh, perverse one,
oh, perverse one,
Baby ソリタリーそんなに甘くないよ でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
Baby, solitary, it's not that sweet, but surely it's not that bad either.
Ah give me fire 火傷しちゃうぜ yeah
Ah give me fire, you'll get burned, yeah.
燃えろよ燃えろよ 炎よ燃え上がれ
Burn, burn, flames, blaze up!
焼チオモヤチオ カワリモセズに ギトのナリトオカシ全部燃やせ ヤオヤオヒチ
Burn them all without change, burn everything strange to ashes!
照れ屋や日向隠す 気が付いて流す涙 ソリタリーそしてワイ 燃える様をお見送り
Hiding in the sunny spots, shedding tears upon realizing, solitary and why, sending off the burning sight.
出し惜しみはしない 濁る真似はできない しがたカルマドラマ 燃やし尽くすマグマドラマ
Holding nothing back, unable to be murky, a fateful karma drama, a magma drama burning it all down.
この赤裸々奇奇怪怪 青い炎みたい 主役過去のひととなり やがて全てひとつとなり
This nakedly bizarre and weird blue flame, the protagonist's past character, soon all becoming one.
World is dying
でもまだ消えてないから
but it hasn't faded yet.
忘れてみたい
I want to try forgetting.
情熱の日はいつしか いつ日にか
The days of passion, someday, somewhere
からだは火照っている 僕らはいつか消やそう
My body is flushed, let's extinguish ourselves someday.
淀みやかに若さを溶かして 泣かないで Why so serious
Melting youth into the murkiness, don't cry, why so serious.
アマノジャキよ
Oh, perverse one,
oh, perverse one,
Baby ソリタリーそんなに甘くないよ でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
Baby, solitary, it's not that sweet, but surely it's not that bad either.
Ah give me fire 火傷しちゃうぜ yeah
Ah give me fire, you'll get burned, yeah.
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Even so, I wanted to dance.
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
燃えそびれたままで 捨ててほど逃げ出すほど
Leaving things half-burnt, wanting to run away so badly...
強くないよ
I'm not that strong.
ほら もう一度 ことばかなる なみかただしか なんて わからないけど
Look, once again... I don't know what's right or true with these words.
形のないものばかりが
Only things without shape
大切になっていく
Keep becoming so precious.
散々巡り 重ならない
Wandering endlessly, overlapping words
言葉だけが強く結ばれてる
Are the only things strongly bound together.
またつまずいて転がって それでも砕けない
Tripping and rolling over, yet never shattering—
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強くなって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and growing stronger, yet I still want to find it—
魂の形確かめてるよ
I'm making sure of the shape of my soul.
深海の底でひとり 扉と鍵を探す
Alone at the bottom of the deep sea, searching for a door and a key.
言いわけは ほら 泡のように全部消え去って
Look, excuses vanish entirely like bubbles.
鼓動を残して 残像だけ
Leaving behind only a heartbeat, an afterimage—
次のページへ 伸びてく枝は離れてく
Growing toward the next page, branches parting ways.
それぞれの道を行く
Each walking their own path.
何重にも罪と寂しさを置いてだけが
Leaving layers of sin and loneliness behind,
強く根を張ってる
Only roots grow deep and strong.
また貫いて釘が刺さって それでもくじけない
Pierced and spiked through, yet refusing to break—
心はどこに 伏線はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the foreshadowing?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Left behind and falling away, yet I still want to convey it—
魂の日々を 魂の石を
The days of the soul, the stones of the soul,
ずっと…
Forever...
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
赤い色ですか
Is it a red color?
青い色ですか
Is it a blue color?
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
太めな過去に 太めな下に 生きるあなたは
Living in a thick past, under a thick foundation—what about you?
何色ですか
What color are you?
またつまずいて転がって それでも砕けない
Tripping and rolling over, yet never shattering—
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強くなって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and growing stronger, yet I still want to find it—
魂の形確かめてるよ
I'm making sure of the shape of my soul.
ずっと…
Forever...
その胸にしまった火に憧れた
I longed for the fire hidden in that chest.
飲み込まれて消されされてしまいそうで
It felt like it would be swallowed up and extinguished.
夕焼けみたいに暖かくて
Warm like a sunset,
寂しくって強かったその日に
Lonely yet strong, on that day—
言葉選んで
Choosing my words...
手探り間違えた　よく晴れた日を
The bright, sunny day when I fumbled and made a mistake,
いまだに思い出す
I still remember it to this day.
目を伏せたらもう　動けなくて
When I cast my eyes down, I could no longer move,
嫌われていないこと祈るばかりさ
Just praying that I wasn't hated.
心全部見せてくれた
You showed me your whole heart,
何ひとつ出来なかったのに
even though I couldn't do a single thing.
どんな今を生きていますか
What kind of present are you living in now?
好きだった歌はまだ聞こえますか
Can you still hear the songs you loved?
くしゃみひとつで笑った横顔
Your profile when you smiled at a single sneeze,
離れてもそばにいる　綺麗でいるよ
Even when apart, you're by my side, staying beautiful.
口実だけで繋いだ　知らないで
Connected only by pretexts, without knowing,
それでも離さない一人は怖い
Even so, being the only one not letting go is scary.
疲れた勢いか　いろんなことが
Driven by exhaustion, all sorts of things
奇跡みたいに思えて　どうしようもない
Felt like a miracle, leaving me completely helpless.
少しずつ感じなくなっていく
Little by little, I stopped feeling it,
悔しかった帰り道　忘れていく
Forgetting the way home wrapped in regret.
そうしなきゃだめな　時が来る
A time must come when I have to do just that,
それでも寂しくないこともある
Yet sometimes, I don't feel lonely at all.
黙ったままの指切り　何が分からないか分からないまま
Remaining silent with pinky promises, not knowing what I don't understand.
星を呼んで　位置を知るように
Calling upon the stars, as if to know my location,
君の声で　僕は進めるんだ
With your voice, I can keep moving forward.
さよならを言った場所から　離れても聞こえるよ　約束が
From the place where we said goodbye, even if far away, I can hear the promise.
その胸にしまった日に憧れた
I longed for the day I tucked it away in my heart,
こんな思い気づかなかったでしょう
Surely I never realized I'd feel this way.
その日がその目に見えなくても
Even if that day is invisible to your eyes,
この真夏の裏には夜空残る
The night sky remains behind this midsummer.
さよならを言った場所には　君の声がずっと輝くんだ
In the place where we said goodbye, your voice keeps shining on forever.
君が君を見失っても　僕が見つけ出せるよ
Even if you lose sight of yourself, I will find you.
どんな今を生きていますか　僕の歌が今
What kind of present are you living in? Can my song now
聞こえますか　くしゃみひとつで取り戻せるよ
Be heard? With a single sneeze, I can take it back.
離れてもそばにいる　綺麗でいるよ
Even when apart, you're by my side, staying beautiful.
ということで「サザンクロス」を歌わせていただきました！
And that's how we performed "Southern Cross"!
ちびにこちゃん、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！でておいで～
Chibi Nico-chan, thanks for singing along with me! Come on out~
わあ！
Wow!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
にこちゃんの
Nico-chan's...
にこちゃんだよ、ちびにこちゃん。
It's Nico-chan, Chibi Nico-chan.
ようやく会えたねってか、
"We finally met," huh?
てか、
I mean,
本当にちっちゃいよね！
you're really small!
かわいい！
So cute!
いや、ありがとう！
No, thank you!
かわいいかわいいって、
Saying "So cute, so cute,"
目の中に入れたくないんだよね、自分だからね。
you don't want to put me in your eye since you are yourself, right?
てか、もう目の中に入れたいね、たべっちゃいたい！
I mean, you want to put it in your eye already, you want to eat it up!
え、ちょっと待って！
Huh, wait a minute!
え、かわいい、かわいいって！
Uh, "So cute, so cute!"
さっきからさっきからにこちゃん怖いんだけど！
Nico-chan, you've been scaring me since a while ago!
ごめんごめん！
Sorry, sorry!
にこちゃん、この後大切なお知らせたくさんしなきゃいけないからさ、
Nico-chan, we have a lot of important announcements after this,
ちょっと待っててくれるかな、このあとの面会で。
so could you wait a bit for the meeting after this?
ゆっくりふれあうね。うん、わかった。
We'll interact slowly. Yeah, understood.
え、とりあえず、にこちゃん！このあとも頑張ってね！バイバイ！
Uh, anyway, Nico-chan! Do your best after this too! Bye-bye!
リスナーさんもバイバイ！
Listeners, bye-bye too!
バイバイ、ちびにこちゃん、えへへ、かわいい！
Bye-bye, Chibi Nico-chan, ehehe, so cute!
ということで、ちびにこちゃんに来ていただきました！
And that's how we had Chibi Nico-chan come join us!
可愛いかったねー
So cute!
配信はまだまだ続くのですが、
The stream is still going,
ここで告知を…いくつかございます。
but I have a few announcements here!
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
小金井ニコ誕生日記念2026のグッズが出まーす！
Koganei Niko's 2026 Birthday Goods are out!
やったー！
Yay!
早速ね、1つずつグッズを紹介させてください。
Let me introduce the goods one by one right away.
1つ目は、こちら！
The first one is this!
清楚ニコたん アクリルジオラスタンド。イラストは本田ロアロ先生に描いていただきました！
Pure Niko-tan Acrylic Diorama Stand. Illustrated by Roaro Honda!
今回の生誕のテーマをもとに、Diva清楚なニコたんをイメージして描いていただいてます！
Based on this year's birthday theme, portrayed as a Diva-like pure Niko-tan!
清楚なニコたんをね、ぜひアクリルジオラスタンドとしておうちにお迎えしてください。
Please welcome pure Niko-tan into your home as an acrylic diorama stand.
お次はこちら！ちびニコたん ランダム缶バッジ。
Next up is this! Chibi Niko-tan Random Can Badge.
今回もグッズ化してしまいました！
We made goods out of them this time too!
いろんな表情やポーズのちびニコたんが全部で4種類。ランダムで1種類だけ入ってます。
There are four kinds of Chibi Niko-tan in various poses. One random type is included.
どのちびニコたんが出てくるかは開けてからのお楽しみ！
Which Chibi Niko-tan you get is a surprise until you open it!
続いてはこちら！ちびニコたんをゼロ距離でぬいぐるみショルダーバッグ！
Next is this! Chibi Niko-tan at zero distance Plush Shoulder Bag!
いつでもどこでもちびニコたんと一緒にお出かけできます。いろんなところに連れてってあげてください。
You can go out with Chibi Niko-tan anytime, anywhere. Please take her everywhere.
あの、頭を開けてね、これ物入れられます。
Um, open up the head, you can put stuff in here.
最後はこちら！獲物を見つけたニコたん ぬいぐるみキーホルダー。
Last is this! "Prey-Spotted Niko-tan" Plush Keychain.
単体で持って行くもよし、さっきのショルダーバッグにつけていくもよし。
Good to carry on its own, or attach to the shoulder bag from earlier.
いろんなところにつけてニコたんを推しアピールできます！
Attach it to various places to show off your love for Niko-tan!
改めてフルセットはこちら！かわいいし美しい！
Here is the full set again! Cute and beautiful!
ちびニコたんを今回もね、グッズにできて、清楚のニコたんもグッズにできて本当に嬉しいです。
I'm really happy we could make goods of Chibi Niko-tan and pure Niko-tan this time too.
使いやすいものも多いのでぜひゲットしてください。
Many are easy to use, so please get them.
さらに！フルセット購入特典もございます！こちら！
Furthermore, there are full set purchase benefits! Here!
フルセット購入特典、直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード。
Full set purchase bonus: ticket-style card with handwritten signature & duplicated message.
これと特典のASMRボイスが出ます。タイトルは野生に戻ってしまった成人女性《虎》（とじ）です。
And the bonus ASMR voice is released. Titled "The Adult Woman Who Returned to the Wild: 《Tiger》".
といことっ！？とじとっ！最後に《虎》ってことは、虎なんだよな？そういうことだよな、グッズさんよ。
What does that mean!? Since it's 《Tiger》 at the end, it's a tiger, right? Right, goods-san?
チケット風カードにはね、あの心を込めて全てに手書きでサインをさせていただきます。
For the ticket-style card, I'll put my heart into it and handwrite my signature on every one.
ボイスは《虎》として野生に戻ってしまったニコたんを取り戻しに行くリスナーというテーマで収録です。
The voice is recorded with the theme of a listener going to retrieve Niko-tan.
ということなんだろう本当に。まあでも超気になりますよね。ね、ぜひ聴いてみてください。
What on earth does that mean? But I'm super curious, right? Please give it a listen.
グッズは配信後カートオープンです。フルセットは数量限定ではございませんのでゆっくり購入してください。
Goods will be available in the cart after the stream. The full set is not limited, so take your time.
大事な告知はまだありますが、その前に1曲歌わしていただこうかなと思います。ちょっとマイクも変えますね。
There are still more announcements, but before that, I'd like to sing a song. I'll change my mic too.
次の曲はニコたんのことをずっと応援してくれてる皆さんにとってもとても思い出深いあの曲となっております。
The next song is a very memorable one for everyone who has continued to support Niko-tan.
それでは聞いてください、ヒカリヘ。
Please listen to it. Hikari e.
理想現実ワンクリック 光の速さに変わっても
With a single click, just as I imagined, even if I change to the speed of light,
地球の裏より遠い距離 アダムとイヴにはなれないから
the distance to the other side of the world—we can never become Adam and Eve.
悲しみの生まれた場所たどって その傷優しく触れて癒せたなら
Tracing back to where sadness was born, if I could gently touch and heal those wounds,
溢れる想い 愛は君を照らす光になれるから
my overflowing feelings and love can become the light that illuminates you.
切ないほどに
So painful it hurts...
たとえ描く未来 そこに私がいなくても
Even if in the future we paint, I am no longer there,
いまはそっと抱きしめてあげる
I will gently hold you close right now.
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I want to pull fate closer and keep shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい 信じたい
I want to believe we can make a miracle happen—I want to believe.
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I want to pull fate closer and keep shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい
I want to believe we can make a miracle happen.
信じた
I believed...
理想現実ワンクリック
With a single click, just as I imagined,
光の速度に変わっても
even if I change to the speed of light.
地球の裏より遠い
Further than the other side of the world,
アダムとイヴにはなれない
we can't become Adam and Eve.
悲しみの生まれた場所辿って
Following the place where sadness was born,
その傷優しく触れて癒せたなら
if I could gently touch and heal that wound...
溢れる想い
My overflowing feelings,
愛は君を照らす光になれる
love can become the light that illuminates you
切ないほどに
to the point of poignancy.
たとえ描く未来
Even if in the future I draw,
そこに私がいないとしても
I'm not there.
今はそっと抱きしめてあげる
I'll gently hold you now.
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I'll even pull fate closer, I want to keep shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい
I believe I can even make a miracle happen,
信じたい
I want to believe.
遠慮配慮言葉の最後
At the end of words of restraint and consideration,
感情記号化されても
even if emotions are turned into symbols,
心の奥まで伝わらない
it doesn't reach the depths of the heart.
ホントの声を聴かせて
Let me hear your real voice.
すべての事に終わりがあるなら
If everything has an end,
苦しみさえいつか消えるはずだから
even suffering should eventually disappear.
溢れる想い
My overflowing feelings,
愛は胸を焦かす痛みに変わる
love changes into a pain that burns my chest,
いとおしいほどに
to the point of being dear.
たとえ世界中の声なき声に責められたとしても
Even if I am blamed by the voiceless voices of the whole world,
私が全部受け止めてあげる
I will gently accept everything.
人は悲しみを知るために生まれてきたの そんなことない もっと知りたい
Were people born to know sadness? That's not true, I want to know more love.
孤独が温もりを知るためにあるのなら 幸せはいつでもそこにあるのに
If loneliness exists to know warmth, happiness is always right there.
溢れる想い
My overflowing feelings,
愛は君を照らす光になれる
love can become the light that illuminates you
尊いほどに
to the point of being precious.
たとえ描く未来
Even if in the future I draw,
そこに私がいないとしても
I'm not there.
今はそっと抱きしめてあげる
I'll gently hold you now.
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I'll even pull fate closer, I want to keep shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい
I believe I can even make a miracle happen,
信じたい
I want to believe.
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I'll even pull fate closer, I want to keep shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい
I believe I can even make a miracle happen,
信じたい
I want to believe.
信じた
I believed...
ということでなんと、みわさんに来ていただきましたー！
And so, Miwa-san has come to join us!
みわさん！
Miwa-san!
わあ、タッチだー！
Wow, high-five!
みわさんだ。かっこいい、触っている。すごい。
It's Miwa-san. So cool, we're touching. Amazing.
みわさんに来ていただきました。
Miwa-san came to visit us.
みわです。
I'm Miwa.
みわさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Miwa-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！めっちゃ嬉しいです。
Thank you so much! I'm so happy.
実は、みわさんとはデビュー初年の歌ってみた「ヒカリヘ」を作らせていただきまして、
Actually, we recorded a cover of "Hikari e" in Miwa-san's debut year,
そのご縁でまさかこうして一緒に歌うことができるなんて本当に夢のようでございます、みわさん。
and never did I dream we'd be able to sing together like this because of that connection, Miwa-san.
こちらこそです。いや、とても嬉しいです。美しかった。
The feeling is mutual. I'm so happy. It was beautiful.
そして、ここでなんと重大な告知、2つめがございます！なんと、みわさんに作詞作曲をしていただいた、
And now, we have a second major announcement! Miwa-san actually wrote and composed...
ニコたん初めてのオリジナル曲が決定してます！
Nikotan's first-ever original song has been decided!
やったー！
Yay!
みわさん、そのタイトルをぜひ発表していただいてもいいでしょうか？
Miwa-san, would you please announce the title?
私でいいんでしょうか？
Is it really okay for me?
当たり前じゃないですか！
Of course it is!
それでは発表させていただきます。
Then I will make the announcement.
お願いします。
Please do.
タイトルは「星円」です。
The title is "Seien" (Circle of Stars).
星円です。星の炎と書いて「星円」です。
"Seien". Written with the kanji for star and flame, "Seien".
実は今回のライブのタイトルにもなってます、「星円 Firefly Diva」。今回のセットリストも星と炎の曲で作られていて、
Actually, it's also the title of this live, "Seien Firefly Diva". The setlist is made up of songs about stars and flames,
今回最後にこれからみわさんに作っていただいた「星円」を歌わせていただきます！
and finally, we will sing "Seien" which Miwa-san made for us!
ニコたんがこうしてホロライブに来て、こうやってみわさんと出会ったり嬉しいこともたくさんありながらもやっぱり活動で悩んだりだとか辛いこととか…
Nikotan coming to Hololive, meeting Miwa-san like this, having many happy moments, but also struggling or facing hard times in activities...
「と」とかそういうものがいっぱいあったんですけど
There were all sorts of things like 'to' and such,
それを全部miwaさんに聴いてもらって、
and I had Miwa-san listen to all of them,
あの歌詞をね、作っていただきました。
and she wrote the lyrics for me.
曲も作っていただきました。本当に皆さん、ありがとうございます！
She composed the music for me too. Thank you all so very much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
もう本当に光栄です。
I'm truly, truly honored.
ねえ、ニコさんの曲一緒にかけれて本当に光栄です。
Hey, it's such an honor to sing Niko-san's song together.
今日一緒に光を歌えて本当に嬉しかったです。本当にありがとうございます！
I was so happy to sing Hikari together today. Thank you so much!
では、このあと歌う新曲「星炎」楽しみにしてるね。
Well, I'm looking forward to your upcoming new song 'Seien'.
私もみんなと一緒にそこで見てるよ！
I'll be watching right there with everyone!
ニコニコにいるのー！
I'll be right there on NicoNico!
皆さんこれからもよろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, thank you for your continued support!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
がんばって！
Do your best!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
あーもうmiwaさん可愛いし、作詞も素敵だし歌声も素晴らしいしもう本当に戻ったら永遠に語っちゃうな。
Ah, Miwa-san is so cute, her lyrics are wonderful, her singing voice is amazing... I could honestly talk about it forever if I went back.
ってことで新曲を畳みにステージ移動したいと思います。聞いてください、「星炎」。
With that, I'd like to move to the stage to perform my new song. Please listen to 'Seien'.
自信なんてなかった
I had no confidence,
ひとりだってよかった
I was fine being alone.
プライドに隠れて 誰かの視線
Hiding behind my pride, I cared too much
気になってばかりで 閉じこもってた
about everyone's gaze and shut myself away.
綺麗だなんて思えなくて
I couldn't think of myself as beautiful,
笑えなかったんだ
and I couldn't smile.
涙でにじんだ 画面の向こう
Beyond the screen blurred with tears,
ふいに溶けた心
my heart suddenly melted.
触れてくれた声
The voice that reached out to me,
「君のおかげで笑えたよ」
"Because of you, I was able to smile."
その言葉がずっと
Those words will forever
この胸を灯す
light up this chest.
ただ一つの光
My only light.
Fire, take me higher 消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Fire, take me higher, turning this fading voice into a song,
弱さ抱きしめながら 届けと叫ぶように
embracing my weakness, shouting so it will reach you,
燃やす炎
burning like a flame.
届けと叫ぶように 燃やす炎
Shouting so it reaches you, burning like a flame.
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to illuminate your tomorrow.
救われたくて 100以上出し切って
Wanting to be saved, giving it over 100%,
疲れ果てた夜
on nights when I was exhausted,
大事なものって なんだっけ
I'd start to forget what was truly important.
忘れそうになるの
振り返る足跡
Looking back at my footprints,
あの頃の自分に会いたい
I want to meet the me of those days.
もう戻れなくても
Even if I can never go back,
素直になりたい
I want to be honest with myself.
失くしたくないから
Because I don't want to lose it.
Fire, take me higher 君への想い歌に乗せて
Fire, take me higher, putting my feelings for you into a song,
恐さ受け止めながら 響けと祈るように
accepting my fears, praying that it resonates,
燃やす炎
burning like a flame.
響けと祈るように 燃やす炎
Praying that it resonates, burning like a flame.
Fire, take me higher
君の笑顔を灯したい
I want to light up your smile.
壊れそうな夜をこえて
Crossing over nights that felt like they'd break,
逃げ出したい朝をぬけて
slipping through mornings I wanted to run from,
いまここにいる
I am right here now.
私のつくる世界で
If you can smile in the world I create,
君が笑ってくれるなら
この声が生まれた理由
the reason this voice was born,
胸に灯る星炎
is the star flame burning in my chest.
Fire, take me higher
私に意味をくれた君へ 声は届いていますか
To you who gave me meaning, are my words reaching you?
Fire, take me higher
私に意味をくれた君へ
To you who gave me meaning,
声は届いてますか
Can you hear my voice?
これからもずっと歩き続けたい
I want to keep walking on forever.
Fire, take me higher
消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Turning this fading voice into a song,
弱さを抱き締めながら
While embracing my weaknesses,
届けと叫ぶように燃やす炎
A burning flame, crying out to reach you.
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to illuminate your tomorrow.
皆さん歌を聴いてくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you everyone for listening to my song!